Guide to the Gerald Robert Vizenor Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- August 2004 Acquisition, 1970-2004; 15.75; (16 boxes)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi," one set of master page proofs with corrections, 209pp, 2004 (Box 50)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi," typescript, 165pp, 2004 (Box 50)
  - "Bear Island: The War at Sugar Point," typescript dated 2/04 with corrections, 43pp, 2004 (Box 50)
  - "Bear Island: The War at Sugar Point," early typescript in a gray notebook dated 10/22/03 with heavy corrections, 2003-2004 (Box 50)
  - "Bear Island: The War at Sugar Point," early notebook of notes and prose drafts dated 1/00, 157pp, 2000 (Box 50)
  - Research materials re: "Bear Island: The War at Sugar Point" and Sugar Point, approx. 200pp, 1998; 2 (Box 50)
  - Notebook: One composition book of holograph notes re: "Bear Island: The War at Sugar Point", 2000 (Box 50)
  - "Jeux de frontieres: L'ecriture poetique dans "Dead Voices" (1992) de Gerald Vizenor" by Najoua Hannachi-Gregolre, bound doctoral thesis re: Vizenor (In French, In three volumes), 795pp, 2003; 3 (Box 50)
  - "(Alter)Native Survivance: Postindian Comedy and Motion In Gerald Vizenor's "Hotline Healers" by Ying-wen Yu, bound academic thesis re: Vizenor, 86pp, 2003 (Box 51)
  - "Literature as Weapon: How Three Native American Writers Have Fought to Sustain Their People's Identity and Presence" by Rob Murdoch, honors thesis (B.A.) re: Vizenor, Leslie Marmon Silko and Sherman Alexie, 48pp, 2004 (Box 51)
  - "Photographers of Native Americans," bound group of seminar papers, Native American Studies, University of California Berkeley, 1982 (Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous publications, pamphlets, brochures, P.R. materials etc. re: Vizenor and the University of Nebraska Press, 2003-2004; 2 (Box 51)
  - Award, 2001 (Box 51)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57" ringbound manuscript, 271pp, 2004 (Box 52)
  - "Jeux de frontieres: L'ecriture poetique dans "Dead Voices" (1992) de Gerald Vizenor" by Najoua Hannachi- Gregoire, doctoral thesis re: Vizenor (in French, in two volumes), 355pp, 2001-2002; 2 (Box 52)
  - "Chancers," ring bound manuscript dated 8/99, 157pp, 1999 (Box 52)
  - "Who Owns the Body?" international conference held at Berkeley in 9/00, correspondence and research material, 2000; 2 (Box 52)
  - "Fugitive Poses: Native American Scenes of Absence and Presence," page proofs of the Japanese translation, 426pp, 1998 (Box 52)
  - Book, "Contemporary Authors/ Autobiography Series: Volume 22" (NY: Gale Research, 1996), includes Vizenor entry, 411 pp (Box 52)
  - Book, "Multiculturalism In Contemporary Societies: Perspectives on Difference and Transdifference" (Erlangen, GER: Erlangen, 2002), includes Vizenor essay, 272pp (Box 52)
  - Book, "Wordarrows: Native States of Literary Sovereignty" by Gerald Vizenor, first wrappers edition, 164pp, 2003 (Box 52)
  - Book, "John Steinbeck: Centennial Reflections by American Writers," includes Vizenor essay, 115pp, 2002 (Box 52)
  - "Interimage Simulations: Fugitive Poses of Native American Indians" by Gerald Vizenor, offprint (two copies), 18pp, undated (Box 52)
  - "A Comprehensive Bibliography: Gerald Vizenor" by Jamie Bunch, 34pp, 2001 (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous publications, pamphlets, brochures, P.R. materials etc. re: Vizenor and the University of Nebraska Press, 2003-2004 (Box 52)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," corrected manuscript (October 2002), 271 pp (Box 52)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," page proofs dated 3-31-03, 210pp, 2003 (Box 53)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," copy-edited typescript with minor corrections, plus cover letter, dated 12/26/02, 289pp, 2002-2003 (Box 53)
  - "Chancers" paperback edition, literary and business correspondence plus cover proofs, P.R. etc., approx. 25pp, 1999-2001 (Box 53)
  - Josef Raab Bielefeld Conference Oct 23-26 2002, "Mister Kennewick's Liberty: Truth Games and Native American Conference Oct 23-26 2002 "Sovereignty," variant drafts of lecture with correspondence, approx. 40pp (Box 53)
  - "Ropes Lecture," variant drafts of paper given at the University of Cincinnati 2/5/02, plus correspondence, 10pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - Louis Owens, "Dear Louis" by Mary Addi, typescript, 148pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - Lauret Savoy, Louis Owens, "Provenance Notes" by Lauret Savoy, typescript plus correspondence with Vizenor re: Louis Owens, 11pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - Book proposal, Louis Owens, approx. 15pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - Louis Owens / Gail Jardine, chronological email correspondence compiled by Jardine with cover letter dated 8/5/02, approx. 200pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - Royalty statements from 2002 (Box 53)
  - "Autobiography Essay," typescript for Gale Research Contemporary Authors book, plus additional biographical info., 2002 (Box 53)
  - "Wordarrows: Native States of Literary Sovereignty," manuscript with corrections and cover letter for the Bison Books paper edition, 2002 (Box 53)
  - "Practice of Dawn: Selections from the Earth Journal" by John Caddy, bound advance reading copy dated 7/18/02 with Vizenor's comments on verso, 100pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - "Transmotion In Wonderland: Reading Gerald Vizenor's Trickster Nonsense," typescript of an academic paper re: Vizenor with correspondence, 33pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - "Chancers: Selected Scenes from the Novel" by Gerald Vizenor from the book "Imaginary (Re-) Locations: Tradition, Modernity, and the Market in Contemporary Native American Literature and Culture" (Stauffenberg Verlag), offprint (four copies), 15pp, 2002 (Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous publications, pamphlets, brochures, P.R. materials etc. re: Vizenor and the University of Nebraska Press, 2002 (Box 53)
  - Business and literary correspondence, approx. 1200pp, 2002-2003; 9 (Box 53)
  - Business and literary correspondence, approx. 1000pp, 2000; 9 (Box 54)
  - Academic Papers (2000), approx. 250pp, 1999 (Box 54)
  - "Chancers," partial draft dated 8/99, 12pp, 1999 (Box 54)
  - "Mister Ishi: Analogies of Exile, Deliverance and Liberty," almost final draft dated 10/29/2000, plus conference programs from "Who Owns the Body?," 16pp (Box 54)
  - "The Everlasting Sky: Introduction," final draft dated 9/2/00, plus second draft, 16pp, 2000 (Box 54)
  - Royalty statements, 2000 (Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous publications, pamphlets, brochures, P.R. materials etc. re: Vizenor and the University of Nebraska Press, 2000 (Box 54)
  - Curtis Seminar, material relating to "Visual Representation and Cultural History: The Edward S. Curtis Photographs of North American Indians" seminar at Claremont Graduate University, October 6-7, 2000, plus drafts of Vizenor's paper, "Edward Curtis: Pictorialist and Ethnographic Adventurist" (Box 54)
  - Business and literary correspondence, 2003; 4 (Box 54)
  - Business and literary correspondence, 2003 (Box 55)
  - "George Morrison: Anishinaabe Expressionism at Red Rock," variant drafts, one dated 4/20/03, 7pp (Box 55)
  - Academic papers (2003), plus one poetry manuscript re: Louis Owens, approx. 40pp (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous publications, pamphlets, brochures, P.R. materials etc. re: Vizenor and the University of Nebraska Press, 2003 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," typescript, 271pp, undated (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," first version dated 8/01 with heavy corrections and rewrites, 58pp, 2001 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," research material, approx. 50pp, 1999-2001 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," early draft with numerous corrections, 1999-2002 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," early draft with numerous corrections, approx. 125pp, 2001 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," early draft with alternate title of "Atomu 57: Hiroshima Kabuki" with numerous corrections, 2001 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," early draft of Chapters 1-16 with numerous corrections, 150pp, 2001 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," early draft of Chapters 17-22 with numerous corrections, 72pp, 2001 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," research material, approx. 100pp, 2002 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," notebook of holograph journal entries of Vizenor's stay in Japan from May 8-18, 2000, approx. 20pp (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," research material, 2000; 2 (Box 55)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi: Atomu 57," research material, 2002; 4 (Box 56)
  - "Matsushima: Haiku" by Gerald Vizenor (Minneapolis, MN: Nodin Press, 1984), heavily annotated author's copy; Color photos of Gerald Vizenor's visit to Hiroshima's Peace Park, 1984-2002 (Box 56)
  - "The Least of These: Miki Sawada and Her Children" by Elizabeth Anne Hemphill (NY: Weatherhlll, 1980), photocopy, 161pp (Box 56)
  - "George Morrison: Anishinaabe Expressionism at Red Rock": variant manuscript drafts w/ corrections of this essay on artist George Morrison, plus research materials, approx. 500pp, 2004 (Box 56)
  - July 2004 Essays, Lectures (Box 56)
    Includes: "Crazy Papers" (7pp); "George Morrison" (21 pp); "Native American Narratives" (27pp); "Imagic Moments" (28pp); "Edward Curtis" (18pp); "Fusions of Survivance" (19pp); "Wordarrows" (15pp); "Mister Ishi" (16pp); "Trickster Hermeneutics" (10pp); "Mercenary Sovereignty" (17pp); "Native American Literature in the 1930s" (6pp); "Native American Survivance" (24pp); Santa Maria Casino" (64 pp)
  - Service Credit Allocation, group of financial records re: University of California, 2002 (Box 56)
  - Student Evaluations 1980s - 1990s, student evaluations re: University of California, 1984-1997 (Box 56)
  - Notebook, "January 1975 Notes," red notebook of holograph entries from January - April, 1975, approx. 70pp (Box 56)
  - Notebook, "1996 - Haiku Place Poems," composition notebook of holograph poetry entries dated June 4, 1991 - May 16, 1993, approx. 24pp, 1991-1993 (Box 56)
  - Notebook, "Plays Dec. 1999," composition notebook of holograph notes re: "The President's Teeth," 3pp (Box 56)
  - Notebook, "Commodity Art /Almost Series," composition notebook of holograph notes of story ideas, approx. 90pp, 1994 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "1984-1988": composition notebook of holograph notes dating from January 1984 - February 1991, approx. 180pp, 1984-1991 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Summer 1991-1995," composition notebook of holograph notes re: story, book and essay topics dating from June 6, 1991- 1995, 160pp (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Manifest/Ishi", composition notebook of holograph notes re: Ishi, approx. 42pp, 1992 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Jews and Indians 1996," composition notebook of holograph notes, approx. 16pp (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Manifest Manners 1991-1992," composition book of holograph notes dating from December 1991, approx. 20pp (Box 57)
  - Notebook, green cloth notebook of misc. holograph notes dating from 1994 and/or 1997, approx. 60pp, 1994-1997 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, black notebook of misc. holograph notes dating from Lake Forest, IL 1970 -1972, approx. 14pp (Box 57)
  - Notebook, untitled black notebook of misc. holograph notes dating from October 18, 1987 - May 1989, approx. 90pp, 1987-1989 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Point Roberts," small blue spiral notebook of misc. holograph notes, approx. 25pp, undated (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "The Healing Brain: San Francisco January 26-27 1980," small blue spiral notebook of notes re: "Healing Brain" symposium, approx. 120pp (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Psychotherapy": blue spiral notebook of notes re: "Psychotherapy" symposium, January 27-28, 1979, approx. 140pp (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Ishi 1994," small blue notebook of notes re: "Ishi" dating from October 1981 - May 1994, 124pp, 1981-1994 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Notes 1983," one small blue notebook of notes from 1983, 37 pp (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Summer 1992," one small blue record notebook of notes from June 18, 1992 to July 1993, approx. 80pp, 1992-1993 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "1980," one small red record notebook of notes from May 1980 - January 19, 1995, approx. 40pp, 1980-1995 (Box 57)
  - Notebook, "Notes for Hiroshima Bugi," one small notebook of notes from July 2, 2000, approx. 180pp (Box 57)
  - Book, "Fugitive Poses: Native American Scenes of Absence and Presence," Japanese language edition, 437pp, 2002 (Box 57)
  - Book, "True West: Authenticity and the American West" (Lincoln, NE, University of Nebraska Press, 2004) includes Vizenor's "Edward Curtis" essay, 370pp (Box 57)
  - Book, "The Everlasting Sky" by Gerald Vizenor (Minnesota Historical Society Press, 2000): paperback edition, 140pp (Box 57)
  - Book, "Cultural Encounters in the New World" (Gunter Narr Verlag, 2003): includes Vizenor's "Mercenary Sovereignty" essay, 457pp (Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous, printed material (Box 58)
  - Business correspondence, approx. 1,500pp, 2001; 9 (Box 58)
  - Business correspondence, approx. 1,500pp, 2001; 3 (Box 58)
  - Business correspondence, approx. 500pp, 2001-2002; 4 (Box 58)
  - Business correspondence, approx. 500pp, 2002-2003; 4 (Box 59)
  - Miscellaneous essays by Vizenor, plus Vizenor bibliography., 2001 (Box 59)
    Includes "The Everlasting Sky: Introduction" (18pp); "Mercenary Sovereignty" (16pp); "Interimage Simulations" (27pp); "Ishi and the Wood Ducks" (51pp).
  - Royalty statements, 2001 (Box 59)
  - Manuscripts (Others), miscellaneous essays, manuscripts and academic papers by other writers, undated; 2 (Box 59)
  - "Literature of Survivance: Three Modes of Contemporary Native American Writing" by Beata Skwarska, bound doctoral dissertation re: Vizenor and others with cover letter, 342pp, 2004 (Box 59)
  - Interviews, various typescripts of interviews with Gerald Vizenor, approx. 100pp, 1993-2004 (Box 59)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi," correspondence with University of Nebraska Press, approx. 100pp, 2002-2004 (Box 59)
  - Native American Narratives, correspondence with University of Nebraska Press, approx. 30pp (Box 59)
  - Japan Lectures Kansai, correspondence with Warren Soiffer re: lecture proposal approx., 20pp, 1992 (Box 59)
  - American Studies 102/Water, Spring 200l, academic materials re: Vizenor's course on water in the West, approx. 50pp, 2000 (Box 59)
  - Wilson, academic materials re: Terry Wilson, approx. 20pp, 1992 (Box 59)
  - Manuscripts (Others), miscellaneous essays, offprints and papers by Vizenor and others, 1999-2002 (Box 59)
  - Book, "Landfill Meditation: Crossblood Stories" by Gerald Vizenor (Hanover, NH: Wesleyan University Press, 1991), signed hard back copy, 201pp (Box 59)
  - Book, "Griever: An American Monkey King In China" by Gerald Vizenor: (Normal, IL: Illinois State University, 1987), signed paper bound copy, 238pp (Box 59)
  - "Chancers," manuscript dated 8/99, 158pp, 1999 (Box 60)
  - "Chancers," manuscript dated 11/99, 162pp, 1999 (Box 60)
  - "Chancers," corrected publisher's manuscript, plus cover proof and letter, 162pp, 1999 (Box 60)
  - "Chancers," author's copy of the page proofs for correcting with minor corrections dated 1/18/00, 159pp, 2000 (Box 60)
  - "Chancers," master copy of the page proofs (unchecked) dated 1/18/00, 159pp, 2000 (Box 60)
  - "Chancers," revised copy of the page proofs dated 2/23/00, 159pp, 2000 (Box 60)
  - "Chancers," bound copy of the page proofs dated 1/18/00 with minor corrections and cover proofs, 159pp, 2000 (Box 60)
  - "Fugitive Poses: Native American Indian Scenes of Absence and Presence," case copy with heavy corrections, approx. 400pp, 1998 (Box 60)
  - "Fugitive Poses: Native American Indian Scenes of Absence and Presence," manuscript dated 1998 with corrections, 337pp (Box 60)
  - "Ishi and the Wood Ducks: Postindian Trickster Comedies: Prologue and Four Acts," ringbound manuscript dated 1994, 51pp (Box 60)
  - "Native American Indian Identity and Postmodernism in the Works of Gerald Vizenor" by Suzanne Harmsen-Peraino, copy of master's thesis, 2000 (Box 60)
  - Notebook, "Telephone June 1996 - November 2000," telephone numbers and contacts, 60pp, 1996-2000 (Box 60)
  - Vizenor Reader, correspondence re: "Gerald Vizenor: A Reader" edited by A. Robert Lee (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous publications, pamphlets, brochures, P.R. materials etc. re: Vizenor and the University of Oklahoma Press, 1998-2000 (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous essays by Vizenor, plus Vizenor curriculum, 1981-2000 (Box 60)
    Includes: "The Everlasting Sky: Introduction" (18pp); "Transethnic Anthropologism" (7pp); "Earthdivers and Shadow Workers" (18pp); and "Bone Counts" (11pp)
  - Appointment calendars, 1991-2001; 3 (Box 60)
  - Genealogies, "Beaulieu and Vizenor Families Genealogies" compiled by Gerald Vizenor, dated January 1983 Minneapolis, MN, approx. 100pp (Box 61)
  - "Ruins of Representation: Shadow Survivance and the Literature of Dominance," two variant typescripts dated October and November of 1992, 31pp (Box 61)
  - "Native American Indian Literatures: An Anthology" edited by Gerald Vizenor, two variant typescripts dated October 1994 (for Harper Collins) (Box 61)
  - "The Everlasting Sky," correspondence with the Minnesota Historical Society Press, approx. 50pp, 2000-01 (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous reviews of Vizenor's works, 1988-1989 (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous reviews of Vizenor's works, 1992 (Box 61)
  - MELUS, copies of Vizenor's essay "Woodland Wood Warrior", 1986 (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and typescripts of essays and articles by Gerald Vizenor and others, approx. 250pp, 1992 (Box 61)
  - Materials re: plagiarism case at UCB, 2002 (Box 61)
  - New Courses, materials re: proposed course outlines, 1992 (Box 61)
  - Promotion merit, UCB, 1999-2003; 2 (Box 61)
  - Academic correspondence, UCB, 1994-1997 (Box 61)
  - Student evaluations, UCB, 2000-2003 (Box 61)
  - Complaint, correspondence from UCB re: teaching assignments, 1997 (Box 61)
  - "Native American Narratives: Resistance and Survivance," two variant typescripts, one dated March 14, 2003, 27pp (Box 61)
  - "Visions, Scares and Stories," page proofs, 22pp, [2003] (Box 61)
  - "Hiroshima Bugi," dust jacket proofs, 2004 (Box 61)
  - "What to Do?: a novel" by Arnold Krupat, ringbound uncorrected galleys with cover letter, 164pp, 2003 (Box 61)
  - "Back-Eyed Boy: Crazy Dog Song Night" by Raymond Pierotti, partial typescript with cover letter, 127pp, 2003 (Box 61)
  - James Hansford C. Vest, typescripts with cover letter, 100pp, 2003 (Box 61)
    Includes: "American Indians and Cinema: Interpretive Essays for Considering Native American Cultures in Film" (24pp); "The Mission: An Allegory of the Conquest" (26pp); and "The Bobtail Stories: Monacan Narratives from the Buzzard Rock Hico, Virginia and Beyond" (50pp)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts (Vizenor), plus Curriculum Vitae, various tearsheets and reviews, approx. 100pp, 2003-04 (Box 61)
    Includes: "George Morrison" (21 pp); "Native American Narratives" (27pp); "The Stories of Survivance" (6pp); "Imagic Moments" (21 pp); "Literary Gambling Sticks" (13pp)
  - Royalty statements, 2003 (Box 61)
  - Geneva April 1-2, correspondence re: trip, 2004 (Box 61)
  - Denman Chair - Texas, 2004 (Box 61)
  - San Antonio, Denman Chair search, 2004 (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous publications, pamphlets, brochures, P.R. materials etc. re: Vizenor and the University of Oklahoma Press, 1999-2004 (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous essays, manuscripts and academic papers by other writers, approx., 250pp, 2003 (Box 62)
  - Business correspondence, approx. 520pp, 2000; 5 (Box 62)
  - Business correspondence, approx. 400pp, 2003; 8 (Box 62)
  - Business correspondence, 2004 (Box 62)
  - Business correspondence, 2004; 8 (Box 63)
  - Videocassettes
    - "Contemporary Native American Authors/Class 20 & 21/Vizenor", undated; YCALMSS539_0004; 1; 01:57:56 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002102339380)
      Restricted fragile material.
    - "Gerald Vizenor Reading 3/9/2000 The American poetry Archive, San Francisco CA", 2000 March 9; YCALMSS539_0005; 1; 01:28:10 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002102339398)
    - "Dana Salisbury from Stone's War": "Laundry Breaks His Promise" 3 min., 2001; YCALMSS539_0006; 1; 00:03:15 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002102339406)
    - The Last of His Tribe, undated; YCALMSS539_0007; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002102339414)
    - "Stone's War" (Against Loneliness and Human Separations from the Natural World)": conceived and directed by Dana Salisbury, inspired by Gerald Vizenor's novel "Dead Voices," 50 min., 2001; YCALMSS539_0008; 1; 00:50:59 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002102339422)
  - "In praise of poetry and prose" rehearsal tape, Papa Sol Kreuger (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990 April; 1; 00:33:29 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002091399676)
    A description of the cassette's contents notes: "A fusion of avant-garde jazz, rock and classical music, composed and arranged to support free improvisation on the electric, and electronically altered guitar."
    Side A / Side B
    1. Prelude to "Dark Night"
    2. Dark Night I
    3. Dark Night II
    4. Windhover II
    5. Windhover III
    1. seventeen chirps
  - seventeen chirps / no swan so fine / spotted horses, Sol Krueger (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990 July 7; 1; 00:18:24 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002091399684)
  - Cover proofs from "Earthdivers: Tribal Narratives of Mixed Descent", 1983 (Box 64 Oversize)
  - Illustrations of Native Americans, undated (Box 64 Oversize)
    Includes: White Swan (Crow), Chief White Buffalo (Arapaho), Thunder Cloud (Blackfeet), Chief Wets It (Assiniboine), High Bear (Sioux), and Chief Red Cloud (Sioux)
  - Miscellaneous publications with Gerald Vizenor articles, 1985-2000 (Box 64 Oversize)
  - Photographs: Two 10" x 10" black and white photographs taken of Vizenor when he was in Germany in 2000 (Box 64 Oversize)
  - Poster: "The Story of A Distinguished Anishinaabe A Presentation by Gerald Vizenor: Expressionist Painter: George Morrison: A Presentation by Gerald Vizenor: February 26, 2004" (Box 64 Oversize)
- June 2008 Acquisition, circa 1976-2008; 11.6; (16 boxes) + 1 object
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Thornton Wilder Memorial Fund, 2008.
  Arrangement
  Organized into five series: Correspondence, Writings, Writings by Others, Academic and Conference Material, and Other Papers.
  This portion of the collection includes correspondence, writings, slides, photographs, clippings, audiovisual material, art work, a typewriter, computer disks, and other papers.
  Box 80 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 1029
  - Correspondence, circa 2001-2008
    - Business and academic, circa 2001-2006; 17 (Box 65)
      Includes 1 computer disk
      Computer disk is restricted. Reference copies of electronic files are available through Access Services:
      Disk #20080530-16443.0001; CD-R, "Thesis 7/9/2005 - Name: Dr. T. C. Brindhakumari"
    - Business and academic, circa 2001-2006; 17 (Box 66)
    - Business and academic, circa 2004-2008; 16 (Box 67)
    - Business and academic, circa 2007-2008; 16 (Box 68)
    - Center Genocide, circa 2006 (Box 68)
      Includes correspondence and contacts concerning a proposed Genocide and Holocaust center.
    - Carmen Manuel Catalan Translation, circa 2006-2007 (Box 68)
      Includes business correspondence with Carmen Manuel regarding a Catalan translation of "Almost Ashore," as well as contracts and an introduction by Vizenor.
  - Writings, circa 1976-2008
    Arranged largely in alphabetical order by title.
    - The Aesthetics of Survivance: Literary Theory and Practice, circa 2007 (Box 69)
      Includes a draft of this lecture with corrections, given at the Nolte Center Institute of Advanced Study at the University of Minnesota on April 9, 2007
    - Almost Ashore: Selected Poems, drafts, publisher's galleys, and related correspondence, circa 2005-2007; 6 (Box 69)
    - Bear Island, drafts, publisher's proofs and galleys, and related correspondence, circa 2004-2006; 8 (Box 69)
    - Bearheart, bound page proofs of the reprint edition, circa 1990 (Box 69)
    - Curriculum vitae, circa 2008 (Box 69)